The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: Good morning, everyone.
教授：大家早上好。
So lecture three of four in the shortest path module and today
因此，在今天最短路径模块中，讲四分之三
we'll finally confront our nemesis,
我们最终将面对我们的克星
which are negative cycles and negative edges.
这是负周期和负边。
And we will describe an algorithm
我们将描述一个算法
that is due to two different people.
那是由于两个不同的人。
They didn't collaborate to produce this algorithm.
他们没有合作产生这种算法。
Bellman and Ford.
贝尔曼和福特。
This computes shortest paths in a graph with negative edges.
这将计算具有负边的图形中的最短路径。
And not only that, even in the graph
不仅如此，即使在图中
has negative cycles in it, the algorithm
算法中有负循环
will be correct in the sense that it
从某种意义上说是正确的
will report the existence of a negative cycle
将报告存在负周期
and, essentially, abort the computation of shortest paths
从本质上讲，中止了最短路径的计算
that are undefined.
未定义的
And for the few vertices that do not
对于一些顶点，
have negative cycles in between them and the source,
在它们和源之间存在负周期，
the algorithm will report correct shortest paths.
该算法将报告正确的最短路径。
So it is a polynomial time algorithm.
因此，这是一个多项式时间算法。
It's fairly easy to describe.
这很容易描述。
And what we'll do is describe it, analyze its complexity
我们要做的就是描述它，分析它的复杂性
and, for once, we'll do a formal proof of its correctness
并且，我们将对其形式做一次正式的证明
to show that it reports the existence of negative cycles
证明它报告了负周期的存在
if they do exist.
如果它们确实存在。
And if they don't exist, it correctly
如果它们不存在，那就正确了
computes shortest path weights.
计算最短路径权重。
So recall that when we look at the general case
所以回想一下，当我们看一般情况时
of the shortest path problem.
最短路径问题。
We're going to have, let's say, a vertex u that, in this case,
假设我们有一个顶点u在这种情况下，
happens to be our source.
恰好是我们的来源。
And let's say for argument's sake
为了争辩而说
that we have a negative weight cycle like so.
我们的负重周期是这样的。
So let me to draw this in bold.
因此，让我以粗体显示。
And this happens to be a negative rate cycle.
这恰好是负利率周期。
Let's assume that all of these edges have positive weights.
假设所有这些边都具有正权重。
Then, if you have an algorithm that
然后，如果您有一种算法
needs to work on this type of graph, what you want
需要处理这种类型的图，您想要什么
to be able to do is to detect that this negative cycle
能够做的就是检测到这个负周期
exists.
存在。
And you're going to, essentially,
从本质上讲，您将要
say if this vertex is v1, for example,
例如说这个顶点是否为v1，
you want to be able to say delta u v1 is undefined and similarly
您希望能够说delta v1是未定义的，并且类似
for v2, v3, et cetera.
对于v2，v3等
For all of these things, the shortest path lengths
对于所有这些事情，最短的路径长度
are undefined because you can essentially
是不确定的，因为您基本上可以
run through this negative cycle any number of times
经历此负面循环多次
and get whatever shortest path weight you want.
并获得所需的最短路径权重。
For this node, let's call that v0, we have delta u v0
对于这个节点，我们称它为v0，我们有del u v0
equals 2.
等于2。
And there's a simple path of length 1
并且有一条长度为1的简单路径
in this case that gets you from u to v0.
在这种情况下，您将从u转到v0。
You don't encounter a cycle or negative cycle in between.
您之间不会遇到周期或负周期。
So that's cool.
太酷了。
All right?
好吧？
And of course, if you have a vertex over here, z,
当然，如果这里有一个顶点z
that can't be reached from u then we're
从你那里无法到达那我们
going to have delta uz being infinity.
会有uz无限大
And you can assume at the beginning of these algorithms
您可以假设在这些算法的开始
that the source-- in this case, I call the source u--
来源-在这种情况下，我称来源u-
but the shortest path to u would be 0.
但通往u的最短路径为0。
And all of the other ones are infinity.
其他所有的都是无限的。
And some of them may stay infinity.
其中一些可能会保持无限。
Some of them may obtain finite shortest path weights.
其中一些可能会获得有限的最短路径权重。
And some of them will be undefined
其中一些将是不确定的
if you have a graph with negative cycles in it.
如果您有一个带有负循环的图形。
So that's sort of the specification, if you will,
所以这就是规范，如果您愿意，
of the requirements on the Bellman-Ford algorithm.
Bellman-Ford算法的要求。
We want it to be able to do all of the things I just described.
我们希望它能够完成我刚刚描述的所有事情。
OK?
好？
So let's take a second look at our generic shortest path
因此，让我们再来看一下通用的最短路径
algorithm that I put up, I think, about a week ago.
我认为大约一个星期前我提出了这个算法。
And this is a good review of our notation.
这是对我们符号的一个很好的回顾。
But there are a couple more things
但是还有两件事
I want to say about this algorithm
我想说一下这个算法
that I didn't get to last time.
我没有去上一次。
So you're given a graph and you set all of the vertices
因此，您得到一个图，并设置了所有顶点
in the graph to have infinite shortest path
在图中具有无限的最短路径
weights, initially.
最初是重量。
Set the predecessors to be null.
将前任设置为null。
And then we'll set d of s to be 0.
然后将的d设为0。
That's your source.
那是你的来源。
And the main loop would be something like repeat,
而且主循环就像是重复，
select, and edge.
选择和边缘。
And we have a particular way of selecting this edge.
我们有一种选择这种优势的特殊方式。
And we have positive edge weights
我们有积极的权重
that corresponds to the minimum priority.
对应于最低优先级。
And we talked about Dijkstra but we have, maybe,
我们谈到了Dijkstra，但也许，
different ways of doing that.
不同的方式。
We have to select an edge somehow.
我们必须以某种方式选择一条边。
And then, we relaxed that edge.
然后，我们放松了优势。
u, v, w.
u，v，w
And you know about the relaxation step.
而且您了解放松步骤。
I won't bother writing it out right now.
我现在就不用再写了。
But it's basically something where
但这基本上是
you look at the value of d v. And if d v
你看d v的值。如果dv
is greater than d u plus the weight, you relax the edge.
大于du加上重量，您可以放松边缘。
And you keep doing this.
而且您继续这样做。
The other thing that you do in the relaxation
放松时要做的另一件事
is to set the predecessor pointers to be correct.
是将先前的指针设置为正确的。
And that's part of the relax routine.
这是放松常规的一部分。
And you keep doing this until you can't relax anymore.
而且您会继续这样做，直到无法放松为止。
All right?
好吧？
So that's our generic shortest path algorithm.
这就是我们通用的最短路径算法。
There are two problems with this algorithm.
该算法有两个问题。
The first, which we talked about and both of these
我们讨论过的第一个
have to do with the complexity but the first one
与复杂性有关，但第一个
is that the complexity could be exponential time,
复杂度可能是指数时间，
even for positive edge weights.
即使对于正的边缘配重。
And the particular example we talked about
还有我们讨论的特定示例
was something where you had an exponential number of paths.
是您的路径数量成指数增长的地方。
And if you had a graph that looks like this,
如果您有一个像这样的图表，
then it's possible that a pathological selection of edges
那么可能是边缘的病理选择
is going to make you relax edges an exponential number of times.
将使您放松边缘的次数呈指数增长。
And in particular, if you have n nodes in this graph,
特别是如果此图中有n个节点，
it's plausible that you'd end up getting
看来你最终会得到
the complexity of order 2 raised to n over 2.
2阶的复杂度提高到2以上的n。
OK?
好？
So that's one problem.
这是一个问题。
The second problem, which is actually
第二个问题，实际上是
a more obvious problem, is that this algorithm might not even
一个更明显的问题是，该算法甚至可能无法
terminate if this-- actually will not
如果终止，实际上不会
terminate the way it's written if there's a negative weight
如果负重，则终止书写方式
cycle reachable from the source.
从源头可到达的周期。
All right, so there's two problems.
好的，所以有两个问题。
We fixed the first one.
我们修复了第一个。
In the case of positive edges are non-negative edges.
在正边缘的情况下是非负边缘。
We have a neat algorithm that is an efficient algorithm called
我们有一个整洁的算法，这是一种称为
Dijkstra that we talked about last time that fixed
上次讨论的Dijkstra修复了
the first part.
第一部分。
But we don't know yet how we're going
但是我们还不知道如何
to handle negative cycles in the general case.
在一般情况下处理负面循环。
We know how to handle negative edges
我们知道如何处理负边缘
in the case of a DAG-- a directed acyclic graph--
就DAG而言-有向无环图-
but not in the general case.
但在一般情况下却不是。
OK?
好？
So there's this great little skit from Saturday Night Live
所以星期六夜现场有个很棒的小品
from the 1980s-- so way before your time-- called The Five
从1980年代开始-在您的时代之前-被称为五
Minute University.
分钟大学。
Anybody seen this?
有人看到吗？
All right.
好吧。
Look it up on YouTube.
在YouTube上查找。
Don't look it up during lecture but afterwards.
演讲时不要查，而是以后查。
So the character here is a person
所以这里的人物是一个人
by the name of-- I forget his real name
以...的名字-我忘记了他的真名
but his fake name is Father Guido Sarducci.
但他的假名叫吉多·萨杜奇神父。
All right?
好吧？
So what's this Five Minute University about?
那这五分钟大学是做什么的？
Five Minute University, he's selling this notion
五分钟大学，他在推销这个概念
and he says, look, five years after you graduate
他说，看，毕业五年后
you, essentially, are going to remember nothing.
从本质上讲，您将什么也不会记住。
OK?
好？
I mean, you're not going to remember anything
我的意思是，你不会记住任何东西
about all the courses you took, et cetera.
关于您参加的所有课程等等
So why waste your time on a college education or waste
那么，为什么要浪费时间在大学教育上呢？
money-- $100,000-- on a college education?
钱-100,000美元-接受大学教育？
You know, for $20 I'll teach you in five minutes what you're
你知道，花20美元，我会在五分钟内教你
going to remember five years after you graduate.
记得毕业五年后
All right?
好吧？
So let's take it to an extreme.
因此，让我们将其发挥到极致。
Here's a 30 second version up 6006.
这是6006的30秒版本。
And this is what I want you to remember five years or 10 years
这就是我要你记住五年或十年
or whatever after you graduate.
或毕业后的其他事情。
All right?
好吧？
And maybe the 10 second version as polynomial time is great.
也许10秒版本的多项式时间很棒。
OK?
好？
Exponential time is bad.
指数时间不好。
And infinite time gets you fired.
而无限的时间会让你被解雇。
OK?
好？
So that's all you need to remember.
这就是您需要记住的所有内容。
No, that's all you need to remember for the final.
不，这就是您在决赛中需要记住的所有内容。
This happens, you know, five years after you graduate.
你知道，这发生在毕业五年之后。
So you need to remember a lot more if you
因此，如果您需要记住更多
want to take your quiz next week and the final exam.
想在下周参加测验和期末考试。
But I think that summarized over here.
但我认为这里总结了一下。
You have a generic shortest path algorithm.
您有一个通用的最短路径算法。
And you realize that if you do this wrong
你会意识到，如果你做错了
you could very easily get into a situation
你很容易陷入困境
where a polynomial time algorithm, and we
多项式时间算法，而我们
know one for Dijkstra, turns into exponential time
为Dijkstra认识一个，变成指数时间
in the worst case, you know, for a graph like that
在最坏的情况下，对于这样的图
because you're selecting edges wrongly.
因为您错误地选择了边缘。
And in particular, that's problem number one.
特别是这是第一问题。
And problem number two is if you have
第二个问题是
a graph that isn't what you expect.
图表不是您所期望的。
In this case, let's say you expected that a graph
在这种情况下，假设您期望
with no negative cycles or maybe not even negative edges in it.
没有负循环，甚至没有负边。
You could easily get into a situation
您很容易陷入困境
where your termination condition is such
您的终止条件是这样的
that your algorithm never completes.
您的算法永远无法完成。
So we need to fix problem number two today
所以我们今天需要解决第二个问题
using this algorithm called Bellman-Ford.
使用称为Bellman-Ford的算法。
And as it turns out, this algorithm
事实证明，这种算法
is incredibly straightforward.
非常简单。
I mean, its complexity we'll have to look at.
我的意思是，我们必须研究它的复杂性。
But from a description standpoint,
但是从描述的角度来看，
it's four lines of code.
这是四行代码。
And let me put that up.
让我提出来。
So Bellman-Ford takes a graph, weights, and a source s.
因此，贝尔曼·福特（Bellman-Ford）采用图表，权重和来源。
And you can assume an adjacency list specification of the graph
您可以假设图的邻接列表规格
or the representation of the graph.
或图形的表示形式。
And we do some initialization.
然后我们进行一些初始化。
It's exactly the same as in the generic case
与一般情况完全相同
except the d values will still be looking at the d values
除了d值之外，仍将查看d值
and talking about the relaxation operation.
并谈论放松操作。
So we do an initialization.
因此，我们进行了初始化。
And then, this algorithm has multiple passes
然后，此算法有多次通过
because for I equals 1 to v minus 1.
因为对于我等于1等于v减去1。
So it does v minus 1 passes roughly order v passes
所以它减去v减去1遍就大致排序了v遍
where v is the number of vertices.
其中v是顶点数。
And in each of these passes for each edge u v belonging to e
并且在这些通过中的每一个中，对于属于e的每个边uv
relaxes every edge.
放松每一条边缘。
And just so everyone remembers, relax u, v, w is if d of v
所有人都记得，放松u，v，w是v的d
is greater than d of u plus w u v then we'll set d v to be--
大于u + w uv的d，那么我们将dv设置为-
and we also set pi v to be u.
并且我们还将pi v设置为u。
OK.
好。
That's relax operation over here.
这是这里的放松操作。
So that's the algorithm.
这就是算法。
And if you know magically that they're
如果你神奇地知道他们是
no negative cycles in the graph.
图中没有负循环。
So if they're no negative cycles in the graph,
因此，如果它们在图中没有负周期，
then after these-- we'll have to prove this.
然后在这些之后-我们必须证明这一点。
But after these v minus 1 passes you're
但是在这些v减1通过之后，
going to get the correct shortest pathways.
以获得正确的最短路径。
OK?
好？
You want to do a little bit more, right?
您想做更多一点，对吗？
I motivated what we want Bellman-Ford to do
我激发了我们希望贝尔曼·福特做的事情
earlier in the lecture.
在讲座的前面。
So you can also do a check.
因此，您也可以进行检查。
So you may not know if they're negative weight cycles or not.
因此，您可能不知道它们是否为负体重循环。
But at this point, you can say I'm
但是在这一点上，你可以说我
going to do one more pass so the v path-- the v
再做一遍，所以v路径-v
is the number of vertices-- over the graph.
是图形上的顶点数。
So for each edge in the graph, if you do one more relaxation
因此，对于图形中的每个边，如果再放松一遍
and you see that d v is greater than d u plus w u v. So
您会看到dv大于du plus wu v。
you're not doing a relaxation.
你没有放松。
You're doing a check to see if you can relax the edge.
您正在检查是否可以放松边缘。
Then report minus v negative cycle exists.
然后报告存在负v负循环。
So this is the check.
这就是支票。
And the first part is the computation.
第一部分是计算。
So that's kind of neat.
所以这很整洁。
I mean, it fit's on a board.
我的意思是，这很合适。
We talk about the correctness.
我们谈论正确性。
The functionality, I hope everyone got.
功能，希望大家都能得到。
Do people understand what's happening here
人们了解这里发生的事情吗
with respect to functionality?
关于功能？
Any questions?
任何问题？
Not about correctness but functionality?
不是关于正确性而是功能？
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: Where does the [INAUDIBLE]
听众：[听不清]在哪里
get used in the formula?
在公式中使用？
PROFESSOR: Oh, it doesn't.
教授：哦，不是。
It's just a counter that makes sure
只是一个可以确保
that you do v minus 1 passes.
你做v减去1遍。
So what's that complexity of this algorithm
那这个算法的复杂度是多少
using the best data structure that we can think of?
使用我们能想到的最佳数据结构？
Anyone?
任何人？
Yeah, go ahead.
是的，继续。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] v plus e if you're using a [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[音频不清晰] v加e（如果您使用的是[音频不清晰]
to access [INAUDIBLE]?
访问[听不清]？
PROFESSOR: v plus e?
教授：v加e？
AUDIENCE: Or v e plus e.
听众：或ve加e。
PROFESSOR: So that would be?
教授：那会是吗？
AUDIENCE: That's using a dictionary?
听众：那是在用字典吗？
PROFESSOR: Yeah, I know. v e plus e would be?
教授：是的，我知道。 ve plus e是吗？
That's correct but.
没错，但是。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Right.
教授：对。
But I mean when do v e plus e you can ignore the e.
但是我的意思是，当做ve plus e时，您可以忽略e。
So say you have just v times e.
因此，说您只有v倍e。
All right.
好吧。
Good.
好。
Here you go.
干得好。
So this part here is v times e.
所以这部分是v乘以e。
And it doesn't really matter.
这并不重要。
I mean, you can use an array structure adjacency list.
我的意思是，您可以使用数组结构邻接表。
It's not like Dijkstra where we have this neat requirement
不像Dijkstra，我们有这个整洁的要求
for a priority queue and there's different ways
优先队列，有不同的方法
of implementing the priority queue.
实现优先级队列的过程。
This part would be order of v e.
这部分将是v e的顺序。
And that gives you the overall complexity.
这给您带来整体复杂性。
This part here is only one pass through the edges.
这里的这部分只是边缘的一遍。
So that's order e, like you said.
就像您说的那样，这就是顺序e。
So the complexities order v e.
因此，复杂度阶为v e。
And this could be large, as I said before in, I think,
正如我之前所说，这可能很大
the first lecture.
第一堂课。
e is order of v square in a simple graph.
e是简单图中v平方的阶数。
So you might end up with a v cubed complexity
因此，您可能最终会获得AV多维数据集的复杂性
if you run Bellman-Ford.
如果您运行Bellman-Ford。
So there's no question that Bellman-Ford
所以毫无疑问，贝尔曼·福特
is, from a practical standpoint, substantially slower
从实际的角度来看，要慢得多
than Dijkstra.
比Dijkstra。
You can get Dijkstra down to linear complexity.
您可以将Dijkstra降低到线性复杂度。
But this would potentially, at least in terms of vertices,
但这至少在顶点上可能会
be cubic complexity.
三次复杂度。
So when you have a chance, you want to use Dijkstra.
因此，如果有机会，您想使用Dijkstra。
And you're forced to use Bellman-Ford
而且您被迫使用Bellman-Ford
because you could potentially have negative weight
因为你可能会负重
cycles while you're stuck with that.
循环，而你一直坚持下去。
All right?
好吧？
OK, so why does this work?
好，那为什么行得通？
This looks a bit like magic.
这看起来有点像魔术。
It turns out we can actually do a fairly straightforward proof
事实证明，我们实际上可以做一个相当简单的证明
of correctness of Bellman-Ford.
Bellman-Ford的正确性。
And we're going to do two things.
我们将做两件事。
We're going to not only show that if negative weight
我们不仅要显示负重量
cycles don't exist that this will correctly
周期不存在，这将正确
compute shorter stats.
计算较短的统计信息。
But we also have to show that it will detect negative weight
但是我们还必须证明它将检测负重
cycles if they in fact exist.
循环，如果它们确实存在。
So there's two parts to this.
因此，有两个部分。
And let's start.
让我们开始吧。
So what we have here for this algorithm
所以我们在这里有这个算法
is that it can guarantee in a graph g equals
可以保证在图中g等于
v E. If it contains no negative weight cycles then
v E.如果不包含负重量循环，则
after Bellman-Ford finishes execution,
贝尔曼·福特完成执行后，
d v equals delta s v for all v belonging to v. All right?
对于属于v的所有v，dv等于delta sv。好吗？
And then there's that.
然后就是那个。
That's the theorem you want to prove.
那就是你要证明的定理。
And the second piece of it is corollary
第二部分是必然的
that we want to prove.
我们想证明的。
And that has to do with the check.
这与支票有关。
And this says if a value of d of v
这表示如果d的值为v
fails to converge after v minus 1
v减1后无法收敛
passes there exists a negative weight cycle reachable from s.
通过时，存在一个从s可以达到的负重量循环。
So those are the two things that we need to show.
这就是我们需要展示的两件事。
I'll probably take a few minutes to do each of these.
我可能要花几分钟来做这些。
That theorem is a little more involved.
该定理涉及更多。
So one of the first things that we
所以我们要做的第一件事
have to do in order to prove this theorem
为了证明这个定理必须做
is to think about exactly what the shortest path corresponds
是在思考最短路径的确切含义
to in a generic sense.
从一般意义上讲
So when we have source vertex s and you have
所以当我们有源顶点，而你有
a particular vertex v then there's
一个特定的顶点v然后
the picture that we need to keep in mind as we try
尝试时需要牢记的图片
and prove this theorem.
并证明这个定理。
So you have v0, v1, v2, et cetera all the way to vk.
因此，您一直拥有v0，v1，v2等，直到vk。
This is my vertex v. This is s.
这是我的顶点v。这是s。
So s equals v0.
所以s等于v0。
V equals vk.
V等于vk。
All right?
好吧？
So I'm going to have a path p.
所以我要走一条路。
That is v0, v1, all the way to vk.
那就是v0，v1，一直到vk。
OK?
好？
How big is k in the worst case?
在最坏的情况下k有多大？
How big is k?
k多大？
Anybody?
有人吗
How big is k?
k多大？
It's up on the black board.
在黑板上。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: v minus 1, right?
教授：v减1，对不对？
Why?
为什么？
What would happen if k is larger than v minus 1?
如果k大于v减去1，会发生什么？
I'd have a cycle.
我要骑自行车。
I'd be visiting a vertex more than once.
我会不止一次访问顶点。
And it wouldn't be a simple path.
这不是一条简单的道路。
Right?
对？
So k is less than or equal to v minus 1 else I'd have a cycle.
所以k小于或等于v减去1，否则我会有一个循环。
OK?
好？
I wouldn't have a simple path.
我没有简单的道路。
And we're looking for the shortest, simple paths
我们正在寻找最短，最简单的路径
because if you ever get to the point
因为如果你能做到这一点
where-- why are we looking for shortest, simple paths?
在哪里-我们为什么要寻找最短，最简单的路径？
Well, in this case, we're looking
好吧，在这种情况下，我们正在寻找
for shortest, simple paths.
最短，最简单的路径。
And if there's a negative cycle, we're
如果有一个负周期，我们就是
in trouble because the shortest path is not
陷入困境，因为最短的路径不是
necessarily the simple path because you
必然是简单的路径，因为您
could go around the cycle a bunch of times.
可能会绕过周期很多次。
I'll get back to that.
我会回到那。
But in the case where we're trying to prove the theorem,
但是在我们要证明该定理的情况下，
we know that no negative cycles exist.
我们知道不存在负周期。
We can assume that no negative cycles
我们可以假设没有负周期
exist for the case of the theorem.
定理的情况下存在。
And we want to show that Bellman-Ford correctly
我们想正确地证明Bellman-Ford
computes each of the shortest path weights.
计算每个最短路径权重。
And in that case, there's no negative weight cycles.
在这种情况下，没有负重量循环。
We're guaranteed that k is less than or equal to v minus 1.
我们保证k小于或等于v减去1。
All right?
好吧？
Everybody buy that?
大家都买吗？
Good.
好。
All right.
好吧。
So that's the picture I want you keep in mind.
这就是我要记住的图片。
Let's dive in and prove this theorem.
让我们深入研究并证明该定理。
And we prove it using induction.
我们用归纳法证明这一点。
So let v be any vertex.
因此，令v为任何顶点。
And let's say that we're looking at a path.
假设我们正在寻找一条道路。
v0, v1, v2, to vk.
v0，v1，v2到vk。
And like I said, from v0 equals s to vk
就像我说的，从v0等于s到vk
equals v. And in particular, I'm not
等于v。尤其是我不是
going to say that this path p is a shortest
会说这条路径p是最短的
path with the minimum number of edges.
边数最少的路径。
So there may be many shortest paths.
因此，可能有许多最短的路径。
And I'm going to pick the one that
我要挑选一个
has the minimum number of edges.
的边数最少。
If there's a unique shortest path, then that's a given.
如果有唯一的最短路径，那就是给定的。
But it may be that I have a path with four edges that
但是可能我有一条带有四个边缘的路径
has the same weight as another path with three edges.
具有与具有三个边的另一条路径相同的权重。
I'm going to pick the one that has three edges.
我将选择具有三个边缘的那个。
OK?
好？
So it may not be unique with respect
因此在尊重方面可能并非唯一
that they're not necessarily unique shortest paths.
他们不一定是唯一的最短路径。
But I can certainly pick one.
但是我当然可以选一个。
And no negative weight cycles implies that p is simple.
而且没有负权重循环意味着p很简单。
And that implies that k is less than or equal to v minus 1,
这意味着k小于或等于v减去1，
which is what I just argued.
这就是我刚才所说的。
Now keep in mind that picture over there to the right.
现在，请记住那张右边的图片。
And basically, the argument is going to go as follows.
基本上，争论将如下进行。
Remember that I'm going to be relaxing
记住我要放松
every edge in each pass of the algorithm.
算法每次通过的每个边缘。
OK?
好？
There's no choices here.
这里没有选择。
I'm going be relaxing every edge in each pass of the algorithm.
我将放松算法每一遍的每个方面。
And essentially, the proof goes as follows.
本质上，证明如下。
I'm going to be moving closer and closer to vk
我将越来越接近vk
and constructing this shortest path at every pass.
并在每次通过时都构建最短的路径。
So at some point in the first pass,
所以在第一遍的某个时刻，
I'm going to relax this edge v0, v1.
我将放松此边缘v0，v1。
OK?
好？
And at that point, thanks to the optimal substructure property,
在这一点上，由于具有最佳的子结构属性，
given that this is the shortest path,
鉴于这是最短的路径，
this has to be a shortest path, as well.
这也必须是最短的路径。
Any subset of the shortest path has to be a shortest path.
最短路径的任何子集都必须是最短路径。
I'm going to relax this edge and I'm
我要放松这一优势，我
going to get the value of delta from s to v1.
将从s到v1获得增量值。
And it's going to be this relaxation that's
这将是这种放松
going to get me that value.
会给我那个价值。
And after the first pass, I'm going to be able to get to v1.
在第一遍之后，我将能够进入v1。
After the second pass, I can get to v2.
在第二遍之后，我可以进入v2了。
And after k passes, I'm going to be able to get to vk.
在k过去之后，我将能够进入vk。
So I'm just growing this frontier one node every pass.
因此，我只是每过一遍就在这个前沿领域发展一个节点。
And that's your induction.
那就是你的归纳。
And you can write that out.
您可以将其写出来。
And I'll write it out here.
我会在这里写出来。
But that's basically it.
但是基本上就是这样。
So after one pass through all of the edges e, we have d of v1
因此，在通过所有边e之后，我们得到了v1的d
to be delta s v1.
是delta s v1。
And the reason for this is because we'll relax.
这样做的原因是因为我们会放松。
We're guaranteed to relax all the edges.
我们保证放松所有的边缘。
And we'll relax the edge v0, v1 during this pass.
在此过程中，我们将放松边缘v0，v1。
And we can't find a shorter path than this path
我们找不到比这条路更短的路
because, otherwise we'd violate the optimum substructure
因为，否则我们将违反最佳子结构
property.
属性。
And that means that it's a contradiction
这意味着这是一个矛盾
that we selected a shortest path in the first place.
首先我们选择了最短路径
So can argue that we have delta s v1 after the first pass.
因此可以辩称，第一遍之后我们有delta s v1。
And this goes on.
这样下去。
I'm going to write out this proof
我要写这个证明
because I think it's important for you guys
因为我认为这对你们很重要
to see the full proof.
查看完整的证明。
But you can probably guess the rest at this point.
但是您可能现在可以猜测其余的内容。
After one pass, that's what you get.
经过一遍，这就是您得到的。
After two passes through e we have
经过两次e之后
d v2 equals delta s v2 because in the second pass
d v2等于delta s v2，因为在第二遍
we're going to relax edge v1, v2.
我们将放宽边缘v1，v2。
So it' a different edge that needs to be relaxed.
因此，这是另一条需要放松的地方。
But that's cool because I'm relaxing all the edges.
但这很酷，因为我正在放松所有边缘。
And I'm going to be able to grow my frontier.
而且我将能够扩大自己的疆界。
I'm going to be able to compute delta s v2 and the end
我将能够计算delta s v2和结束
of my second pass and so on and so forth.
我的第二遍，等等。
So after k passes, we have d vk equals delta s vk.
因此，经过k次之后，我们的d vk等于delta s vk。
And if I run through v minus 1 passes, which
如果我通过v减去1遍，
is what I do in the algorithm, all reachable vertices
是我在算法中所做的，所有可到达的顶点
have delta values.
具有增量值。
All right?
好吧？
That's basically it.
基本上就是这样。
Any questions?
任何问题？
It's actually a simpler proof than the Dijkstra proof,
它实际上比Dijkstra证明更简单，
which I just sketched last time.
我上次刚刚绘制的草图。
I'll just give you some intuition
我会给你一些直觉
of the Dijkstra proof.
Dijkstra证明。
It's probably a little too painful to do in a lecture.
在讲课中做起来可能有些痛苦。
But this one is, as you can see, nice and clean and fits
但是，正如您所看到的，这是一个不错的，干净的，合适的
on two boards, which is kind of an important criterion here.
在两个板上，这在这里是一个重要标准。
So good.
这么好。
All right, so that takes care of the theorem.
好的，这样就可以处理定理。
Hopefully you're all on board with the theorem.
希望大家都支持该定理。
And one thing that we haven't done is talk about the check.
我们还没有做的一件事就是谈论支票。
So the argument with respect to the corollary
所以关于推论的争论
bootstraps this particular argument for the theorem.
引导定理的这个特定论点。
But this requires the insight that if after v
但这需要洞察力
minus 1 passes, if you can find an edge that can be relaxed,
负1遍，如果您发现可以放松的边缘，
well what does that mean?
那是什么意思？
So at this point, let's say that I've done my v minus 1 passes
因此，在这一点上，假设我已经完成了v减1遍
and we find an edge that can be relaxed.
我们发现可以放松的边缘。
Well, this means that the current shortest path from s
好吧，这意味着当前距离s的最短路径
to some vertex that is obviously reachable v
到一些显然可以达到的顶点
is not simple once I've relaxed this edge because I
一旦放松了这一优势，这并不简单，因为我
have a repeated vertex.
具有重复的顶点。
So that means it's not simple to have a repeated vertex that's
因此，这意味着要重复一个顶点并不简单
the same as I found a cycle.
就像我发现一个周期一样。
And it's a negative weight cycle because I
这是负的体重循环，因为我
was able to relax the edge and reduce the weight after I
我之后能够放松边缘并减轻体重
added a vertex that cost a cycle.
添加了一个花费一个周期的顶点。
All right?
好吧？
So this cycle has to be negative weight.
因此，这个周期必须是负重量。
Found a cycle that is negative weight.
发现一个负重的周期。
All right.
好吧。
That's pretty much it.
就是这样。
So it's, I guess, a painful algorithm
我想这是一个痛苦的算法
from a standpoint of it's not particularly smart.
从它的角度来看不是特别聪明。
It's just relaxing all of the edges
只是放松所有的边缘
a certain fixed number of times.
一定的固定次数。
And it just works out because you will find these cycles.
它之所以奏效，是因为您会发现这些循环。
And if you keep going, it's like this termination condition.
而且，如果您继续前进，就像终止条件一样。
What is neat is that I don't have the generic shortest path
整洁的是，我没有通用的最短路径
algorithm up there anymore.
算法了。
But in effect, what you're saying
但是实际上，你在说什么
is after a certain number of passes,
经过一定次数的通过之后
if you haven't finished, you can quit
如果还没有完成，可以退出
because you have found a negative cycle.
因为您发现了一个负周期。
So it's very similar to the generic shortest path
因此，它与通用最短路径非常相似
algorithm.
算法。
You're not really selecting the edges.
您并不是真正选择边缘。
You're selecting all of them, in this case.
在这种情况下，您要选择所有这些。
And you're running through a bunch of different passes.
您正在经历一系列不同的过程。
All right?
好吧？
So that's it with respect to Bellman-Ford.
就贝尔曼-福特而言就是这样。
I want to do a couple of special cases
我想做几个特殊情况
and revisit the directed acyclic graph.
并重新查看有向无环图。
But stop me here if you have any questions about Bellman-Ford.
但是，如果您对贝尔曼福特有任何疑问，请在这里停下来。
You first and then back there.
你先，然后回到那里。
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: Maybe I'm just confused
听众：也许我只是感到困惑
about the definition of a cycle.
关于循环的定义。
But if you had, like, a tree, which had a negative weight
但是如果您有一棵负重的树
edge, wouldn't it produce the same situation
边缘，会不会产生相同的情况
where you relaxed that edge.
在那放松的地方。
PROFESSOR: But you would have relaxed that edge previously.
教授：但是您以前会放松这种优势。
AUDIENCE: But it wouldn't be a cycle, right?
听众：但这不是一个周期，对吗？
PROFESSOR: Yeah, it wouldn't be a cycle.
教授：是的，这不是一个周期。
So let's look at that.
因此，让我们来看一下。
That's a fine question.
这是一个很好的问题。
AUDIENCE: Doesn't that make assumptions
听众：不是做假设
about this structure?
关于这个结构？
PROFESSOR: Well if you had a tree-- I mean,
教授：如果你有一棵树，我是说，
a tree is a really simple case.
一棵树是一个非常简单的案例。
But if you had something like this
但是如果你有这样的事情
and if you did have a minus 1 edge here,
如果您的边缘确实有负1，
right-- we'll do a more complicated example.
是的-我们将做一个更复杂的例子。
But let's say you had something like this.
但是，假设您有这样的事情。
2 3 minus 1.
2 3减1。
And what will happen is if this happens to be your s vertex
如果这恰好是您的顶点，将会发生什么
and in the first step you relax all the edges.
第一步，放松所有边缘。
And this one would get two.
而这个将得到两个。
And then, depending on the order in which you relaxed,
然后，根据您放松的顺序，
it's quite possible that if you relax this edge first--
如果您先放松这一优势，很有可能
let's say in the first pass the ordering of the relaxation
假设在第一遍中放松的顺序
is 1, 2, and 3.
是1、2和3。
So the edges are ordered in a certain way each time,
因此，每次以某种方式对边缘进行排序，
and you're going to be relaxing the edges in exactly
而且您将完全放松边缘
the same order each time.
每次相同的顺序。
All right?
好吧？
It doesn't matter.
没关系
The beauty of Bellman-Ford is that-- let's say
贝尔曼·福特的美丽在于-可以说
you relax this edge.
您可以放松这一优势。
Initially, this is at infinity.
最初，这是无限的。
So this is at 0.
所以这是0。
This is at infinity.
这是无限的。
If you relax this edge, nothing happens.
如果放松此边缘，则什么也不会发生。
All right?
好吧？
Then you relax, let's say, this edge because that's number two.
然后，您放松一下，说这条边缘，因为那是第二个。
This gets set to two.
这将设置为两个。
You relax this edge because that's 3.
您放宽此边缘，因为那是3。
And this is infinity so nothing happens.
而且这是无限的，所以什么也没有发生。
Of course, this is already at two so nothing would happen.
当然，已经是两点了，所以什么也不会发生。
So the end of the first pass, what you have is this is 0.
因此，第一遍的结尾是0。
That's 2.
那是2
This is still infinity.
这仍然是无限的。
That's still infinity.
那仍然是无限的。
OK?
好？
That's going to stay infinity because you can't reach it
这将保持无限，因为您无法达到它
from s.
来自。
So we can, sort of, ignore that.
因此，我们可以忽略它。
And then, of the second pass, what you have is
然后，第二遍，您拥有的是
you start with this edge again because that's the ordering.
您再次从该边缘开始，因为这是顺序。
And this 2 minus 1 would give this a 1.
而这2减1会得到1。
And then you relax this edge or try to relax this edge.
然后放松该边缘或尝试放松该边缘。
Nothing happens.
什么都没发生。
Try to relax this edge.
尝试放松这一优势。
Nothing happens.
什么都没发生。
And at this point, you have one more pass
此时，您还有一个通行证
to go because you got 4 vertices.
去，因为你有4个顶点。
And in that past, nothing changes again.
在过去，没有任何改变。
So that's what you end up with.
这就是最终的结果。
You end up with 2 for this and 1 for that.
您最终为此得到2个，为此得到1个。
OK?
好？
That makes sense?
那讲得通？
So the important thing to understand
所以重要的是要了解
is that you are actually relaxing
是你实际上在放松
all of the edges in every pass.
每一次通过的所有边缘。
And there's a slightly more complicated example
还有一个稍微复杂的例子
than this that is in the notes.
比注释中的要多。
And you can take a look at that offline.
您可以离线查看。
There's another question in the back.
后面还有另一个问题。
Did you have a question?
你有问题吗
Someone raised their hand.
有人举手。
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: Yes, I'm just curious--
听众：是的，我很好奇
is there a unknown better algorithm that
有没有更好的未知算法
can do the same thing?
可以做同样的事情吗？
PROFESSOR: No, there's no known better algorithm
教授：不，没有已知更好的算法
for solving the general case like this.
解决这样的一般情况。
There are a couple of algorithms that assume weights
有几种假设权重的算法
within a certain range.
在一定范围内。
And then there complexities include both v and e, as well
然后复杂度也包括v和e
as w where w is the dynamic range of the weights.
as w其中w是权重的动态范围。
And depending on what w is, you could
根据w是什么，您可以
argue that they have better complexity.
认为它们具有更好的复杂性。
But they're kind of incomparable in the sense
但是它们在某种意义上是无与伦比的
that they have this extra parameter, which
他们有这个额外的参数，
is the dynamic range of the w.
是w的动态范围。
OK?
好？
Now there's lots of special cases,
现在有很多特殊情况
like I said, and well take a look at the DAG special case
就像我说的，好好看看DAG的特殊情况
in a second where you could imagine doing better
在一秒钟内，您可以想象做得更好
but not for the case where you have an arbitrary graph that
但不适用于您拥有任意图
could have negative cycles in it because it's got negative rate
可能会有负周期，因为它的负利率
edges.
边缘。
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: In the corollary, does that assume
听众：在推论中，假设
you have a connected graph because, you know,
您有一个连通的图，因为，您知道，
you could have a negative weight edge
你可能负重边
in a separate part of the graph, which
在图的单独部分中，
isn't reachable from this.
由此无法达到的。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So you're going to start when you have an undefined weight.
因此，当您的体重不确定时，您将开始学习。
Remember your initialization condition.
记住您的初始化条件。
What is affected by s?
s受什么影响？
Initialize is affected by s.
初始化受s的影响。
The rest of it isn't affected by s
其余部分不受s的影响
because you're just relaxing the edges.
因为你只是放松自己的边缘。
Initialize is affected by s because d of s
初始化受s的影响，因为s的d
starts out being 0, like I put over here, and the rest of them
开始是0，就像我放在这里一样，其余的
are infinity.
是无限的
So there is an effect of the choice of the starting vertex.
因此，存在选择起始顶点的效果。
And the rest of it follows that you
剩下的就是你
will get an undefined value, or you
将获得一个未定义的值，否则您
will find that negative cycle exists
会发现存在负周期
based on whether you can reach it from s or not.
根据您是否可以从到达。
So if you happen to have s over here,
因此，如果您碰巧在这里，
and it's just the one node, and then
这只是一个节点，然后
it has no edges going out of it, this algorithm
它没有边缘掉出来，这个算法
would just be trivial.
只是微不足道的。
But it wouldn't detect any negative cycles
但它不会检测到任何负周期
that aren't reachable from s.
无法从s获得。
That make sense?
有道理？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: So there is this-- it's kind of hidden over there.
教授：就是这样-它藏在那儿。
So I'm glad you asked that question.
所以我很高兴你问了这个问题。
But initialize is setting things up.
但是初始化是在设置东西。
And that is something that affects
那就是影响
the rest of the algorithm because d of s is 0
该算法的其余部分，因为s的d为0
and the rest of them are set to infinity.
其余的都设为无穷大。
All right?
好吧？
So if there are no other questions,
因此，如果没有其他问题，
I'll move on to the case of the DAG
我将继续讨论DAG的情况
and talk a little bit about shortest paths versus longest
谈论最短路径与最长路径
paths.
路径。
And this is somewhat of a preview of a lecture
这有点像演讲的预告片
that Eric is going to give a month from now on complexity
埃里克将从现在开始为期一个月的复杂性
and the difference between polynomial time and exponential
以及多项式时间和指数的差
time, though I'm not going to go into much depth here.
时间，尽管我在这里不打算深入探讨。
But there's some interesting relationships
但是有一些有趣的关系
between the shortest path problem and the longest path
在最短路径问题和最长路径之间
problem that I'd like to get to.
我想解决的问题。
But any other questions on this?
但是还有其他疑问吗？
OK, so let me ask a question.
好，让我问一个问题。
Suppose I wanted to find longest paths in a graph
假设我想在图中找到最长的路径
and let's say that this graph had all positive edge weights.
假设该图具有所有正边权重。
OK.
好。
What if I negated all of the edge weights
如果我否定所有边缘权重怎么办
and ran a Bellman-Ford?
然后跑了贝尔曼福特（Bellman-Ford）？
Would I find the longest path in the graph?
我会在图中找到最长的路径吗？
Do people understand the question?
人们了解这个问题了吗？
I don't need this.
我不需要这个
So maybe we can talk about what a longest path means first.
因此，也许我们可以先谈谈最长路径的含义。
So if this was s and this v1, v2, v3, fairly straightforward,
因此，如果这是s并且此v1，v2，v3非常简单，
you know how to compute shortest paths now.
您现在知道如何计算最短路径。
These are all positive.
这些都是积极的。
Even easier.
甚至更容易。
The longest path to v3 is of length.
到v3的最长路径是长度。
Six because I go here, go there, and go there, right?
六，因为我去这里，去那里，然后去那里，对吗？
So that's my longest path.
所以这是我最长的路。
OK?
好？
And the shortest path to v3 is of length 4.
到v3的最短路径是长度4。
So shortest path, longest paths, have these nice duality.
因此，最短路径，最长路径具有这些良好的对偶性。
What if I said, well, you know, I
如果我说，好吧，你知道吗，我
can solve the longest path problem, as well,
也可以解决最长路径问题
given all of what I've learned about shortest paths
给出了我所了解的最短路径的所有信息
simply by negating each of these edges and running Bellman-Ford.
只需消除这些优势并运行Bellman-Ford。
What would happen?
会发生什么？
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] shortest path branch [INAUDIBLE]
听众：[听不清]最短路径分支[听不清]
values, and if you switched to absolute value,
值，如果您切换为绝对值，
it will give you the longest path.
它会给你最长的路径。
PROFESSOR: So you think it works?
教授：那么您认为它可行吗？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
It will also check the cycles.
它还将检查周期。
So the negative cycles will be the longest path cycles that
因此负周期将是最长的路径周期
[INAUDIBLE].
[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: But I think that's the key question.
教授：但是我认为这是关键问题。
What will Bellman-Ford do when it is run on this?
Bellman-Ford在此基础上运行将做什么？
What would it return?
它会返回什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: No, what will Bellman-Ford return?
教授：不，贝尔曼·福特会返回什么？
I'm asking.
我问。
Someone else?
其他人？
What will Bellman-Ford return if I ran this?
如果执行此操作，Bellman-Ford将返回什么？
Undefined.
未定义。
Right?
对？
Undefined because you got this negative weight cycle here.
未定义，因为您在这里遇到了负体重循环。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Sorry?
教授：对不起？
Oh!
哦!
Let's put another one in there.
让我们再放一个。
Oops, sorry.
哎呀，对不起。
Now I see.
现在我明白了。
You're right.
你是对的。
I'm wrong.
我错了。
And why did you say undefined?
你为什么说未定义？
AUDIENCE: I was wrong.
听众：我错了。
PROFESSOR: OK, good.
教授：好的，很好。
I got company.
我有陪伴
Thank you.
谢谢。
Good.
好。
Let's take it all over again.
让我们再来一遍。
All over again.
再来一遍。
All right.
好吧。
All right, start over.
好吧，重新开始。
s v1 v2 v3.
v1 v2 v3。
Yeah, that is a cycle.
是的，那是一个周期。
All right, good.
好，好
Cycle.
周期。
So when you actually negate each of these edges,
因此，当您实际上否定这些优势时，
you end up with a negative weight cycle.
最终导致负重循环。
So it's plausible that you could have a graph like this one
因此，您可能会有像这样的图
where this strategy won't work because what would happen
这种策略行不通的地方，因为会发生什么
is Bellman-Ford would come back with, essentially, an abort
是Bellman-Ford基本上会放弃
that says I can't compute shortest paths because they're
那说我不能计算最短路径，因为它们
undefined.
未定义。
All right?
好吧？
Now it turns out it's actually more subtle than that.
现在事实证明，它实际上比这更微妙。
What we're trying to do in Bellman-Ford is, in the case
在这种情况下，我们在贝尔曼福特公司试图做的是
where negative weight cycles don't exist,
负负周期不存在的地方
we report on the shortest simple path.
我们报告最短的简单路径。
That's the whole notion of the proof.
这就是证明的全部概念。
We say that the path has a certain length, which
我们说路径有一定的长度，
is, at most, v minus 1 and so on and so forth.
最多为v减去1，依此类推。
We get the shortest simple path.
我们得到最短的简单路径。
But if you actually have a problem where you say-- let
但是，如果您实际上在说什么时有问题-让
me start over again.
我重新开始。
Let's say I want to find the shortest simple path
假设我想找到最短的简单路径
for a different graph and it happens
对于不同的图，它发生了
to have a negative weight cycle in it.
负体重循环。
So I have something like this.
所以我有这样的事情。
2 3 minus 6, 3 over here, 3 over here, and so on.
2 3减去6，这里的3，这里的3，依此类推。
Maybe 2 here.
也许在这里2。
And I want to find the shortest simple path that
我想找到最短的简单路径
reaches v from s.
从s到达v。
OK?
好？
What is the shortest simple path that reaches v from s?
从s到达v的最短简单路径是什么？
It's this path that goes horizontally,
这条路是水平的
which has a weight 3 plus 2, 5, 5
权重为3加2、5、5
plus 3, 8, 8 plus 3, 11, 11 plus 2, 13.
加3、8、8加3、11、11加2、13。
All right?
好吧？
So the shortest simple path is 13.
因此，最短的简单路径是13。
Will Bellman-Ford give you any information about this path?
Bellman-Ford会为您提供有关此路径的任何信息吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: No because in [INAUDIBLE].
教授：否，因为在[音频不清晰]中。
After it does its v minus 1 passes, v is reachable from s.
在完成v减1之后，v可从s到达。
But you potentially go through a negative weight cycle
但您可能会经历负体重循环
before you reach v. OK?
在到达v。OK之前？
So it turns out that if you have a graph with negative weight
事实证明，如果您的图表权重为负
cycles, finding the shortest simple path
循环，找到最短的简单路径
is an NP-hard problem.
是一个NP难题。
It's a really hard problem.
这是一个非常困难的问题。
That's what NP means.
那就是NP的意思。
No, it means something else that Eric
不，这意味着埃里克还有别的东西
will explain to you in a month or so.
会在一个月左右的时间内向您解释。
But it means that we don't know any algorithm that
但这意味着我们不知道任何算法
is better than exponential time to solve this problem.
比指数时间更好地解决了这个问题。
OK?
好？
So amazingly, all you've done is taken the shortest path problem
令人惊讶的是，您所做的全部都是最短路径问题
and changed it ever so slightly.
并做了些微的改动
You said I want to look for the shortest simple path
您说我想寻找最短的简单路径
in the general case where I could, potentially,
在一般情况下，我可能会
have negative weight cycles in my graph.
我的图表中的负重周期为负。
And when you do that, all bets are off.
而当您这样做时，所有赌注都关闭了。
You're not in the polynomial time complexity domain anymore.
您不再处于多项式时间复杂度域中。
At least, not that we know of.
至少不是我们所知道的。
And the best that you can do is an exponential time algorithm
而您能做的最好的就是指数时间算法
to find shorter simple paths.
查找较短的简单路径。
And this problem, as it turns out,
事实证明，这个问题
is equivalent to the longest path problem in the sense
在某种意义上等同于最长路径问题
that they're both NP-hard.
他们都是NP-hard。
If you can solve one, you could solve the other.
如果您能解决一个，就可以解决另一个。
So to summarize, what happens here simply
综上所述，这里发生的只是
is that in the case of Bellman-Ford
是在贝尔曼福特的情况下
running on the original shortest path problem,
在最初的最短路径问题上运行
you're allowed to abort when you detect the fact that there's
当您发现有
a negative cycle.
负循环。
So given that you're allowed to abort when there's
因此，鉴于存在以下情况，您可以中止
a negative cycle, you have a polynomial time solution
负周期，您有多项式时间解
using Bellman-Ford that is not necessarily
使用Bellman-Ford不一定
going to give you shortest path weights but will
将为您提供最短的路径权重，但会
in the case of no negative cycles.
在没有负周期的情况下。
All right?
好吧？
But if you ask for more-- a little bit more-- you said,
但是如果您要求更多（多一点），您说，
you know, it'd be great if you could somehow
你知道的，如果可以的话，那会很棒
process these negative cycles and tell me
处理这些负面周期并告诉我
that if I had a simple path and I don't go through cycles what
如果我有一条简单的道路而我不经历循环
would the shortest weight be, it becomes
重量最短会变成
a much more difficult problem.
一个更加困难的问题。
It goes from order of ve complexity
从复杂度的顺序
to exponential time complexity to the best of our knowledge.
据我们所知，时间复杂度成指数增长。
So that's what I'd like to leave you with.
这就是我想带您离开的地方。
That there's much more to algorithms than just the ones
算法的意义远不止这些
that we're looking at.
我们正在寻找。
And we get a little bit of a preview
我们得到了一些预览
of this-- so the difference between polynomial time
这样-多项式时间之间的差
an exponential time-- later on in the term.
指数时间-该词的后面。